# Shalabh Arora

C/Lagasca, 2D-142, Madrid, Spain | +34 627.099.683 | Sarora.imba2014@student.ie.edu

# **Professional summary**

Investment banking professional with over 5 years of experience in providing transaction advisory and diligence services in Manufacturing, Real Estate, e-Commerce and Telecommunication Services sectors. Demonstrated skills in financial modeling, business valuation, due diligence and assurance for clients from different industries. Fluent in more than three languages.

### Education

### IE BUSINESS SCHOOL | MBA

APR 13-MAY' 14

- · Selected courses M&A, Corporate Finance, Investment Analysis, Private Equity, Sustainable Business Models, Strategy
- · Core GPA 3.5/4, ranked in top10% of intake
- · Recipient of IE Foundation Scholarship,
- · GMAT 720, Coordinator, IE Finance Club

### INSTITUTE OF CHARTERED ACCOUNTANTS OF INDIA | CHARTERED ACCOUNTANT

2006-2010

- · Selected courses Corporate Finance, Strategic Financial Management, Law, Economics, Risk Management, Income taxes.
- · Merit list holder, Ranked 44 across India, UAE and Nepal;
- · Cleared all levels in first attempt with distinction (top 1%)

### UNIVERSITY OF DELHI | BACHELORS OF COMMERCE (HONORS)

2005-2008

- · Selected courses included Corporate Finance, Economic Theory, Business Mathematics, International Business
- · Awarded scholarship for highest marks in Corporate Finance in 2007
- · First division in all years with an overall average of 71% (top 5%)

# **Experience**

### INTERN, INVESTMENTS | UNIQUEST INFRA VENTURES (IDFC AND UEM GROUP) | NEW DELHI

DEC'13-MAR'14

- · Long term investor in infrastructure projects in India backed by IDFC Ltd and UEM Group Berhad, Malaysia
- · Responsibilities include preparing financial model for greenfield projects, due diligence and analysis on potential targets and assisting team in monitoring existing assets in portfolio

#### ASSOCIATE, TRANSACTION ADVISORY SERVICES | ERNST & YOUNG | NEW DELHI

2011-2012

- · Key member of transaction advisory team with experience across manufacturing and communication service industries.
- · Proficient in financial modelling, industry analysis and market dynamics, effectively presenting the client's strategy and business through information memoranda, value metrics and financial performance, using public information and analyst reports to aid a successful deal process
- · Kev transactions
- Performed business model review and financial analysis for the second largest education services company in India. Identified annual savings of \$500 thousand from change in transaction structure with franchises. Commended for detailed deliverables and creative problem solving. Successfully helped client procure \$8.5 million to finance K-12 projects
- · Successfully led a team of three on financial diligence of a packaging company and praised for probing skills. Client requested our data tables for future formal reporting by the investee. Effectively completed engagement resulting in raising \$6.5 million for expansion projects for the client

### SENIOR, ASSURANCE SERVICES (STARTED AS ANALYST) | KPMG | NEW DELHI

2008-2011

- Engagement leader for the assurance team associated with clients across manufacturing, real estate and service industries. Promoted directly to Senior in place of Executive after 2 years as Analyst Key engagements
- · Successfully led multiple assurance and review assignments for an export oriented manufacturing client (turnover \$150 million) listed on the National Stock Exchange of India. Awarded as "exceptional performer" for effective leadership skills
- · Core team member responsible for formulating client specific audit procedures and coordinating among various teams for beverage and snacks divisions of PepsiCo India. Successfully formulated a multipart consumption analysis of Pepsi's operations

## Additional information

- · Languages: English (fluent), German (intermediate), Spanish (basic), Hindi and Punjabi (native)
- · Proficient in Bloomberg, Capital IQ, and other industry databases. Bloomberg Aptitude Test (BAT) 620 (95th Percentile)
- · Initiated set up of KPMG Football Club. Led team to silver medal honors in Cry Cadence Corporate Olympics, 2009
- · Enjoy travelling, reading biographies and an avid follower of Manchester United FC